<archimate:Resource
    xmlns:archimate="http://www.archimatetool.com/archimate"
    name="Service Registry"
    id="820c8c31-db3e-4e7e-9ad4-9b62c08c10f0"
    documentation="The ABB is responsible for allowing advertising and discovery of available services and supports the runtime binding of services and service virtualization. Think of this ABB as a runtime service repository. Services are available to the solution as well as governance processes. Advertisement of services should be governed. It contains metadata about services, including descriptions of the service contract, information about the QoS policies and security, versioning information, and runtime information such as end-points. This ABB may leverage the design-time Service Repository ABB to fetch metadata about services to fulfill the runtime needs of SOA such as dynamic/runtime binding and service virtualization. Standards for registries include UDDI.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;This ABB contains service definitions at runtime and it plays a key role in service virtualization and service discovery. Service virtualization in this context is the exposure of a service end-point through a “proxy” (the registry). This in particular supports agility through service versioning so that the impact of services being released can be addressed through versions of services. The other aspect is the administration of the service where there are changes to the location of a service. Location is expressed in terms of an “end-point”; aka, the location from which a service is invoked. This could be the service container’s address or some other unique identifier (URI).">
  <properties
      key="difi:namespace"
      value="togsoara"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:type"
      value="archi:resource"/>
  <properties
      key="label"
      value="${name}"/>
  <properties
      key="difi:language"
      value="en"/>
  <properties
      key="difi:name_no"/>
  <properties
      key="difi:name_en"
      value="Service Registry"/>
  <properties
      key="difi:description_no"/>
  <properties
      key="difi:description_en"
      value="The ABB is responsible for allowing advertising and discovery of available services and supports the runtime binding of services and service virtualization. Think of this ABB as a runtime service repository. Services are available to the solution as well as governance processes. Advertisement of services should be governed. It contains metadata about services, including descriptions of the service contract, information about the QoS policies and security, versioning information, and runtime information such as end-points. This ABB may leverage the design-time Service Repository ABB to fetch metadata about services to fulfill the runtime needs of SOA such as dynamic/runtime binding and service virtualization. Standards for registries include UDDI.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;This ABB contains service definitions at runtime and it plays a key role in service virtualization and service discovery. Service virtualization in this context is the exposure of a service end-point through a “proxy” (the registry). This in particular supports agility through service versioning so that the impact of services being released can be addressed through versions of services. The other aspect is the administration of the service where there are changes to the location of a service. Location is expressed in terms of an “end-point”; aka, the location from which a service is invoked. This could be the service container’s address or some other unique identifier (URI)."/>
</archimate:Resource>
