<archimate:Resource
    xmlns:archimate="http://www.archimatetool.com/archimate"
    name="Data Sourcing Manager"
    id="dcae185f-e171-4944-8c09-093d585506ad"
    documentation="This ABB is responsible for enabling access to different data sources using different protocols. It provides unified access to data in files, databases, etc. It uses an Adapter ABB from the Integration Layer to provide the ability to integrate with data sources in different solution platforms (external data sources).&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;Examples may be relational sources (e.g., DB2, Oracle, or SQL Server databases), other structured data (e.g., Excel .CSV, web service request responses in XML format, and hierarchical stores on mainframes such as IMS), as well as unstructured data stores (such as images and documents). It manages interactions with the data sources in the Solution Platform and other SOA RA layers, but it is not responsible for addressing data and protocol transformation. This ABB represents the actual data repositories in various types, such as a DB2 database in the Operational Systems Layer, or an Excel file. It should be noted that this ABB in the Information Layer refers to high-level links associated with metadata to real data sources in the Operational Systems Layer. This ABB enables optimization of the data access by lazy loading or on-demand access of information. For example, instead of containing (e.g., attaching) a huge document, this ABB typically contains an on-demand link to the original document, together with some metadata describing the document (e.g., goals, purposes, and short descriptions) that help users decide whether they need to access the original document (e.g., a CEO may decide not to download a detailed design document while a project architect may decide to download and review). In addition, it should be noted this ABB typically represents industry-specific data structure; therefore, transformation may be needed for further processing.">
  <properties
      key="difi:namespace"
      value="togsoara"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:type"
      value="archi:resource"/>
  <properties
      key="label"
      value="${name}"/>
  <properties
      key="difi:language"
      value="en"/>
  <properties
      key="difi:name_no"/>
  <properties
      key="difi:name_en"
      value="Data Sourcing Manager"/>
  <properties
      key="difi:description_no"/>
  <properties
      key="difi:description_en"
      value="This ABB is responsible for enabling access to different data sources using different protocols. It provides unified access to data in files, databases, etc. It uses an Adapter ABB from the Integration Layer to provide the ability to integrate with data sources in different solution platforms (external data sources).&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;Examples may be relational sources (e.g., DB2, Oracle, or SQL Server databases), other structured data (e.g., Excel .CSV, web service request responses in XML format, and hierarchical stores on mainframes such as IMS), as well as unstructured data stores (such as images and documents). It manages interactions with the data sources in the Solution Platform and other SOA RA layers, but it is not responsible for addressing data and protocol transformation. This ABB represents the actual data repositories in various types, such as a DB2 database in the Operational Systems Layer, or an Excel file. It should be noted that this ABB in the Information Layer refers to high-level links associated with metadata to real data sources in the Operational Systems Layer. This ABB enables optimization of the data access by lazy loading or on-demand access of information. For example, instead of containing (e.g., attaching) a huge document, this ABB typically contains an on-demand link to the original document, together with some metadata describing the document (e.g., goals, purposes, and short descriptions) that help users decide whether they need to access the original document (e.g., a CEO may decide not to download a detailed design document while a project architect may decide to download and review). In addition, it should be noted this ABB typically represents industry-specific data structure; therefore, transformation may be needed for further processing."/>
</archimate:Resource>
