<archimate:Resource
    xmlns:archimate="http://www.archimatetool.com/archimate"
    name="Service Container"
    id="f57534a2-afb4-4d1e-8a3e-baad2a650eb0"
    documentation="This ABB acts as a container or gateway by providing the environment with the ability to invoke and run services (manage their runtime invocation, lifecycle, etc.). The Service Container is also commonly known as a Service Gateway. The primary responsibility of the Service Container is to encapsulate the code that implements the low-level details of communicating with a service into this ABB. Some Service Containers require capabilities beyond basic communication, such as transactions and security.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;Thus, its key communication and virtualization responsibilities include the invocation and execution of services, encapsulating the components that implement the service (i.e., providing the service end-points), state management, and the binding of service invocations to cross-cutting layers (such as the Integration Layer and the Business Process Layer in particular), the clustering of services, and their distribution to different consumers.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;It should be noted that all ABBs (including the Service Container) are instantiated in the Operational Systems Layer. For instance, a Service Container may be contained within a J2EE environment or a .NET environment. It is also possible for it to be a hardware device as long as it provides the ABBs required with the ability to support runtime invocation and running of services and integration with cross-cutting layers.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;Within the Service Container are ABBs which enable it to invoke and execute service components, and support the integration with the cross-cutting layers – the Quality of Service Layer, Integration Layer, and Governance Layer. It leverages the Service Repository ABB and Service Registry ABB in the Governance Layer to support service versioning and virtualization.">
  <properties
      key="difi:namespace"
      value="togsoara"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:type"
      value="archi:resource"/>
  <properties
      key="label"
      value="${name}"/>
  <properties
      key="difi:language"
      value="en"/>
  <properties
      key="difi:name_no"/>
  <properties
      key="difi:name_en"
      value="Service Container"/>
  <properties
      key="difi:description_no"/>
  <properties
      key="difi:description_en"
      value="This ABB acts as a container or gateway by providing the environment with the ability to invoke and run services (manage their runtime invocation, lifecycle, etc.). The Service Container is also commonly known as a Service Gateway. The primary responsibility of the Service Container is to encapsulate the code that implements the low-level details of communicating with a service into this ABB. Some Service Containers require capabilities beyond basic communication, such as transactions and security.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;Thus, its key communication and virtualization responsibilities include the invocation and execution of services, encapsulating the components that implement the service (i.e., providing the service end-points), state management, and the binding of service invocations to cross-cutting layers (such as the Integration Layer and the Business Process Layer in particular), the clustering of services, and their distribution to different consumers.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;It should be noted that all ABBs (including the Service Container) are instantiated in the Operational Systems Layer. For instance, a Service Container may be contained within a J2EE environment or a .NET environment. It is also possible for it to be a hardware device as long as it provides the ABBs required with the ability to support runtime invocation and running of services and integration with cross-cutting layers.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;Within the Service Container are ABBs which enable it to invoke and execute service components, and support the integration with the cross-cutting layers – the Quality of Service Layer, Integration Layer, and Governance Layer. It leverages the Service Repository ABB and Service Registry ABB in the Governance Layer to support service versioning and virtualization."/>
</archimate:Resource>
