<archimate:Grouping
    xmlns:archimate="http://www.archimatetool.com/archimate"
    name="Governance Layer"
    id="id-2a3aea0c-83c9-11e9-27b3-44850074a0ae"
    documentation="== Overview&#xD;&#xA;SOA governance ensures that the services and SOA solutions within an organization are adhering to the defined policies, guidelines, and standards that are defined as a function of the objectives, strategies, and regulations applied in the organization and that the SOA solutions are providing the desired business value. SOA governance activities shall conform to corporate, IT, and enterprise architecture governance principles and standards. The Governance Layer will be adapted to match and support the target SOA maturity level of the organization.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;The Governance Layer includes both SOA governance (governance of processes for policy definition, management, and enforcement) as well as service governance (service lifecycle). This covers the entire lifecycle of the services and SOA solutions (i.e., both design and runtime) as well as the portfolio management of both the services and SOA solutions managing all aspects of services and SOA solutions (e.g., Service-Level Agreement (SLA), capacity and performance, security and monitoring).&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;This layer can be applied to all the other layers in the SOA RA. From a Quality of Service (QoS) and management perspective, it is well connected with Quality of Service Layer. From a service lifecycle and design-time perspective, it is connected with the Services Layer. From an SOA solution lifecycle perspective, it is connected to the Business Process Layer.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;The goal of the Governance Layer is to ensure consistency of the service and solution portfolio and lifecycles processes. In this layer, the extensible and flexible SOA governance framework will ensure that all aspects of SOA are managed and governed, such as:&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;* SLAs based on QoS and Key Performance Indicators (KPIs)&#xD;&#xA;* Capacity and performance management policies&#xD;&#xA;* Design-time aspects, such as business rules &#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;The value of this layer is to ensure that the mechanisms are in place to organize, define, monitor, and implement governance from an enterprise architecture and solution architecture view.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;== Context and Typical Flow&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;This layer features the following characteristics:&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;* Defines policies, compliance, and exception characteristics&#xD;&#xA;* Monitors the health of SOA services, solutions, and governance&#xD;&#xA;* Reports on compliance, exceptions, service health, and versions&#xD;&#xA;* Provides a consolidation point for business rules &#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;The Governance Layer is aligned with the standardized SOA Governance Framework [25] which defines an SOA Governance Reference Model and SOA Governance Vitality Method. These provide definitions and best practices for defining a customized governance regimen for the enterprise.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;The SOA Governance Reference Model includes definitions and best practices for governance guidelines, roles/responsibilities, governing processes, governed processes, and governance technology.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;The governing processes are used to fulfill the responsibilities of the Governance Layer:&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;* Compliance processes are the conformance processes and policies including vitality which ensure the continued relevance of key governance model constructs, such as reference models, lifecycle (activities, work products), etc.&#xD;&#xA;* Dispensation processes are processes and policies to handle exception to compliances.&#xD;&#xA;* Communication processes disseminate and educate the fundamental constructs of lifecycle, governance models, etc. &#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;The Governance Layer would have elements that facilitate and enable the implementation of the above governance processes.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;Governed processes for the SOA solution are defined across all the other layers of the SOA RA, but can be articulated as:&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;* Service lifecycle management processes – describe the activities, roles, and work products to the modeling of services throughout the lifecycle, from identification to instantiation and retirement. These are often an extension of the organization’s software development lifecycle.&#xD;&#xA;* Solution lifecycle management processes – describe the activities, roles, and work products as they relate to the modeling of SOA solutions throughout the lifecycle, from identification to retirement.&#xD;&#xA;* Service portfolio management processes – describe activities for selecting services to be developed and services to be re-used by solutions, ensuring an organization has the services appropriate to its needs. This influences the lifecycle management of those services.&#xD;&#xA;* Solution portfolio management processes – describe activities for selecting solutions to be implemented and maintaining the correct mix of assets to support those solutions according the needs of the enterprise. Identifying services need by the solutions is one of the responsibilities and ties directly to input to the Service Portfolio Manager. &#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;The SOA Governance Vitality Method phases, Plan/Define/Implement/Monitor, defined with best practices ensure that governance is a long-term process, keeping business and SOA solutions aligned:&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;* The Plan governance phase is responsible for analyzing, arranging, and scheduling solution-level monitoring and management.&#xD;&#xA;* The Define governance phase is responsible for defining a solution-specific SOA-based governance control model and strategy.&#xD;&#xA;* The Implement governance phase is responsible for enabling and realizing solution-level governance control.&#xD;&#xA;* The Monitor governance phase is responsible for monitoring and managing solution-level system status according to predefined governance policies and plans. &#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;These processes and tasks can be accomplished with a set of technical capabilities and Architecture Building Blocks (ABBs). ABBs implement the capabilities needed by the responsibilities and processes of the Governance Layer. Capabilities and ABBs will be needed for both dimensions of governance, the processes needed to create it, the governance vitality method, and the governance regimen itself. Capabilities and ABBs aligned with that standard are defined here.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;The SOA Governance Vitality Method phases, Plan, Define, Implement, and Monitor, all require the capability to store and access governance information, define policies with a policy manager, and possibly develop and configure management tools. In addition, the Monitor phase needs the ability to monitor metrics, manage and enforce policies, and use change control and configuration management tools to react to policy changes. In addition, workflow can be used to implement the compliance processes.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;The governance regimen – i.e., the customized compliance, dispensation, and communication processes to govern the SOA lifecycle and portfolio management – requires capabilities to store and access governance artifacts, manage and enforce policy, monitor metrics, and manage the configuration of the solution and governance. Change control may be needed to support changes to the system.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;Governance applies to all phases of the SOA solution lifecycle, from architecture and design to implementation and maintenance.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;Governance can be scoped to the enterprise as a whole, a line of business, a particular SOA solution, or a particular set of critical SOA processes and services.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;== Capabilities&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;There are a set of categories of capabilities that the Governance Layer needs to support in the SOA RA.cesses. ">
  <properties
      key="drill down"
      value="95389b60-6d60-4722-a93e-f5e9b34bfd60"/>
  <properties
      key="difi:namespace"
      value="togsoara"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:type"
      value="archi:grouping"/>
  <properties
      key="label"
      value="${name}"/>
  <properties
      key="difi:language"
      value="en"/>
  <properties
      key="difi:name_no"/>
  <properties
      key="difi:name_en"
      value="Governance Layer"/>
  <properties
      key="difi:description_no"/>
  <properties
      key="difi:description_en"
      value="== Overview&#xD;&#xA;SOA governance ensures that the services and SOA solutions within an organization are adhering to the defined policies, guidelines, and standards that are defined as a function of the objectives, strategies, and regulations applied in the organization and that the SOA solutions are providing the desired business value. SOA governance activities shall conform to corporate, IT, and enterprise architecture governance principles and standards. The Governance Layer will be adapted to match and support the target SOA maturity level of the organization.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;The Governance Layer includes both SOA governance (governance of processes for policy definition, management, and enforcement) as well as service governance (service lifecycle). This covers the entire lifecycle of the services and SOA solutions (i.e., both design and runtime) as well as the portfolio management of both the services and SOA solutions managing all aspects of services and SOA solutions (e.g., Service-Level Agreement (SLA), capacity and performance, security and monitoring).&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;This layer can be applied to all the other layers in the SOA RA. From a Quality of Service (QoS) and management perspective, it is well connected with Quality of Service Layer. From a service lifecycle and design-time perspective, it is connected with the Services Layer. From an SOA solution lifecycle perspective, it is connected to the Business Process Layer.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;The goal of the Governance Layer is to ensure consistency of the service and solution portfolio and lifecycles processes. In this layer, the extensible and flexible SOA governance framework will ensure that all aspects of SOA are managed and governed, such as:&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;* SLAs based on QoS and Key Performance Indicators (KPIs)&#xD;&#xA;* Capacity and performance management policies&#xD;&#xA;* Design-time aspects, such as business rules &#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;The value of this layer is to ensure that the mechanisms are in place to organize, define, monitor, and implement governance from an enterprise architecture and solution architecture view.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;== Context and Typical Flow&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;This layer features the following characteristics:&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;* Defines policies, compliance, and exception characteristics&#xD;&#xA;* Monitors the health of SOA services, solutions, and governance&#xD;&#xA;* Reports on compliance, exceptions, service health, and versions&#xD;&#xA;* Provides a consolidation point for business rules &#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;The Governance Layer is aligned with the standardized SOA Governance Framework [25] which defines an SOA Governance Reference Model and SOA Governance Vitality Method. These provide definitions and best practices for defining a customized governance regimen for the enterprise.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;The SOA Governance Reference Model includes definitions and best practices for governance guidelines, roles/responsibilities, governing processes, governed processes, and governance technology.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;The governing processes are used to fulfill the responsibilities of the Governance Layer:&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;* Compliance processes are the conformance processes and policies including vitality which ensure the continued relevance of key governance model constructs, such as reference models, lifecycle (activities, work products), etc.&#xD;&#xA;* Dispensation processes are processes and policies to handle exception to compliances.&#xD;&#xA;* Communication processes disseminate and educate the fundamental constructs of lifecycle, governance models, etc. &#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;The Governance Layer would have elements that facilitate and enable the implementation of the above governance processes.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;Governed processes for the SOA solution are defined across all the other layers of the SOA RA, but can be articulated as:&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;* Service lifecycle management processes – describe the activities, roles, and work products to the modeling of services throughout the lifecycle, from identification to instantiation and retirement. These are often an extension of the organization’s software development lifecycle.&#xD;&#xA;* Solution lifecycle management processes – describe the activities, roles, and work products as they relate to the modeling of SOA solutions throughout the lifecycle, from identification to retirement.&#xD;&#xA;* Service portfolio management processes – describe activities for selecting services to be developed and services to be re-used by solutions, ensuring an organization has the services appropriate to its needs. This influences the lifecycle management of those services.&#xD;&#xA;* Solution portfolio management processes – describe activities for selecting solutions to be implemented and maintaining the correct mix of assets to support those solutions according the needs of the enterprise. Identifying services need by the solutions is one of the responsibilities and ties directly to input to the Service Portfolio Manager. &#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;The SOA Governance Vitality Method phases, Plan/Define/Implement/Monitor, defined with best practices ensure that governance is a long-term process, keeping business and SOA solutions aligned:&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;* The Plan governance phase is responsible for analyzing, arranging, and scheduling solution-level monitoring and management.&#xD;&#xA;* The Define governance phase is responsible for defining a solution-specific SOA-based governance control model and strategy.&#xD;&#xA;* The Implement governance phase is responsible for enabling and realizing solution-level governance control.&#xD;&#xA;* The Monitor governance phase is responsible for monitoring and managing solution-level system status according to predefined governance policies and plans. &#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;These processes and tasks can be accomplished with a set of technical capabilities and Architecture Building Blocks (ABBs). ABBs implement the capabilities needed by the responsibilities and processes of the Governance Layer. Capabilities and ABBs will be needed for both dimensions of governance, the processes needed to create it, the governance vitality method, and the governance regimen itself. Capabilities and ABBs aligned with that standard are defined here.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;The SOA Governance Vitality Method phases, Plan, Define, Implement, and Monitor, all require the capability to store and access governance information, define policies with a policy manager, and possibly develop and configure management tools. In addition, the Monitor phase needs the ability to monitor metrics, manage and enforce policies, and use change control and configuration management tools to react to policy changes. In addition, workflow can be used to implement the compliance processes.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;The governance regimen – i.e., the customized compliance, dispensation, and communication processes to govern the SOA lifecycle and portfolio management – requires capabilities to store and access governance artifacts, manage and enforce policy, monitor metrics, and manage the configuration of the solution and governance. Change control may be needed to support changes to the system.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;Governance applies to all phases of the SOA solution lifecycle, from architecture and design to implementation and maintenance.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;Governance can be scoped to the enterprise as a whole, a line of business, a particular SOA solution, or a particular set of critical SOA processes and services.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;== Capabilities&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;There are a set of categories of capabilities that the Governance Layer needs to support in the SOA RA.cesses. "/>
</archimate:Grouping>
