<archimate:Grouping
    xmlns:archimate="http://www.archimatetool.com/archimate"
    name="Consumer Layer"
    id="id-2a3aea00-83c9-11e9-27b3-44850074a0ae"
    documentation="== Context and Typical Flow&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;The Consumer Layer is the point where consumers interact with the SOA. It enables an SOA to support a client-independent, channel-agnostic set of functionality, which is separately consumed and rendered through one or more channels (client platforms and devices). Thus, it is the point of entry for interactive consumers (humans and other applications/systems) and services from external sources (e.g., Business-to-Business (B2B) scenarios).&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;In fact the Consumer Layer is the entry point for all external consumers, external to the SOA. This can be other systems, other SOAs, cloud service consumers, human users, etc.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;This decoupling between the consumer and the rest of the underlying SOA provides organizations with the ability to support agility, enhanced re-use, and improve quality and consistency. Channels can be thought of as the platforms by which SOA consumers access services through the SOA. Examples of channels would be web front-ends, and IVR (Interactive Voice Response) systems, which could both leverage the same core functionality within the SOA.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;It is thus important to note that SOA decouples the user interface (channel), and thus the consumer, from the components and the implementation of the functionality. Examples of this include Service Component Architecture (SCA) Components [10], portlets, WSRP (Web Services for Remote Portlets 2.0) [14], and B2B integration interfaces. Thus, the SOA enables us to cater for human interactive interfaces (user interfaces) as well as system (application or software) consumers.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;The Consumer Layer is that part of the SOA which enables channel-independent access to business processes and services supported by various applications and platforms. This is important for the effective use and adoption of the SOA.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;Thus, the Consumer Layer provides the capabilities required to deliver IT functions and data to end users and as the entry point for consumers into the SOA RA. These capabilities enable specific users to customize preferences, integrate with consumer channels, including rich clients (mashups and Ajax [20]) and act as a mechanism for the underlying SOA to expose its functionality. Standards (such as WSRP) may leverage services at the application interface or presentation level. Its capabilities include the ability to quickly create the front end of the business processes and the composite applications to respond to changes in the market. It provides the point where in-bound consumer requests have security and other Quality of Service (QoS) policies asserted to ensure that the request is secure and brought into the context of the SOA.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;The Consumer Layer provides the ability to integrate services from within the SOA, and the ability to transform, integrate, and personalize information into the content and mediate with the consumer channels (both for user and non-user interfaces).&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;== Capabilities&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;There are multiple categories of capabilities that the Consumer Layer needs to support in the SOA RA.">
  <properties
      key="drill down"
      value="1fbd72c7-4f31-466b-84e1-b57da669df3f"/>
  <properties
      key="difi:namespace"
      value="togsoara"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:type"
      value="archi:grouping"/>
  <properties
      key="label"
      value="${name}"/>
  <properties
      key="difi:language"
      value="en"/>
  <properties
      key="difi:name_no"/>
  <properties
      key="difi:name_en"
      value="Consumer Layer"/>
  <properties
      key="difi:description_no"/>
  <properties
      key="difi:description_en"
      value="== Context and Typical Flow&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;The Consumer Layer is the point where consumers interact with the SOA. It enables an SOA to support a client-independent, channel-agnostic set of functionality, which is separately consumed and rendered through one or more channels (client platforms and devices). Thus, it is the point of entry for interactive consumers (humans and other applications/systems) and services from external sources (e.g., Business-to-Business (B2B) scenarios).&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;In fact the Consumer Layer is the entry point for all external consumers, external to the SOA. This can be other systems, other SOAs, cloud service consumers, human users, etc.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;This decoupling between the consumer and the rest of the underlying SOA provides organizations with the ability to support agility, enhanced re-use, and improve quality and consistency. Channels can be thought of as the platforms by which SOA consumers access services through the SOA. Examples of channels would be web front-ends, and IVR (Interactive Voice Response) systems, which could both leverage the same core functionality within the SOA.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;It is thus important to note that SOA decouples the user interface (channel), and thus the consumer, from the components and the implementation of the functionality. Examples of this include Service Component Architecture (SCA) Components [10], portlets, WSRP (Web Services for Remote Portlets 2.0) [14], and B2B integration interfaces. Thus, the SOA enables us to cater for human interactive interfaces (user interfaces) as well as system (application or software) consumers.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;The Consumer Layer is that part of the SOA which enables channel-independent access to business processes and services supported by various applications and platforms. This is important for the effective use and adoption of the SOA.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;Thus, the Consumer Layer provides the capabilities required to deliver IT functions and data to end users and as the entry point for consumers into the SOA RA. These capabilities enable specific users to customize preferences, integrate with consumer channels, including rich clients (mashups and Ajax [20]) and act as a mechanism for the underlying SOA to expose its functionality. Standards (such as WSRP) may leverage services at the application interface or presentation level. Its capabilities include the ability to quickly create the front end of the business processes and the composite applications to respond to changes in the market. It provides the point where in-bound consumer requests have security and other Quality of Service (QoS) policies asserted to ensure that the request is secure and brought into the context of the SOA.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;The Consumer Layer provides the ability to integrate services from within the SOA, and the ability to transform, integrate, and personalize information into the content and mediate with the consumer channels (both for user and non-user interfaces).&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;== Capabilities&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;There are multiple categories of capabilities that the Consumer Layer needs to support in the SOA RA."/>
</archimate:Grouping>
