<archimate:Grouping
    xmlns:archimate="http://www.archimatetool.com/archimate"
    name="Operational Systems Layer"
    id="id-ffb84377-83c6-11e9-27b3-44850074a0ae"
    documentation="== Overview&#xD;&#xA;All runtime elements of architecture reside in this layer. Effectively, this layer can conceptually be thought of as the runtime or deployment time of the solution. If we conduct a thought experiment and “freeze” the operations within this layer in a frame of time and expand it out, we will discover the separation of concerns that tend to cluster building blocks within the architecture: the aspects most closely connected with the consumption of the services, the processes that are choreographed into a flow, the services whose interfaces are exposed for consumption, the Service Components that will ultimately be used to realize the implementation of the services, along with the other four major cross-cutting and supporting concerns (integration, information, Quality of Service (QoS) factors, and governance).&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;== Context and Typical Flow&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;This layer describes the runtime and deployment infrastructure; the programs, platforms, application servers, containers, runtime environments, packaged applications, virtual machines, etc. that are on the hardware and are needed to support the SOA solution. These specifically include:&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;* All software and hardware infrastructure necessary to support the SOA and its components at runtime and design time (tools)&#xD;&#xA;* All operational and runtime hosting of underlying physical system components&#xD;&#xA;* All assets required to support the functionality of services in the SOA, including custom or packaged application assets, new services, services created through composition or orchestration, infrastructure services, etc. &#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;This layer represents a “snapshot” and logical categorization and generalization of the runtime environment. As such, this layer supports all the capabilities of the infrastructure that are needed for running/executing all software. Therefore, this layer supports the execution of the capabilities and responsibilities of the other layers of the SOA RA, including the components implementing the services; i.e., those components that a service relies on for providing it with its functional capabilities.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;For example, if we have a capability for an SOA that involves systems using mainframe and J2EE platforms, the Operational Systems Layer would instantiate the necessary Architecture Building Blocks (ABBs) in the Integration Layer and Service Component Layer and the underlying mainframe and J2EE components which provide the functional capability.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;We can express this as a formula such as:&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;Operational Systems Layer = [Infrastructural elements of all other layers] + [Underlying infrastructure to run the infrastructural elements (i.e., Operating Systems, etc.)] + [Elements that realize the Functional Components of services]&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;Thus this layer provides the building blocks supporting the operational systems which implement the functional capabilities of the other horizontal layers and the supporting/cross-cutting layers. In particular, the capabilities supported by this layer include providing operational and runtime hosting, infrastructure services and infrastructure virtualization, functional delivery support including support for service implementations, and realizations.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;== Connection Point with Other Initiatives or Standards&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;This layer represents the intersection point between the actual runtime infrastructure and the rest of the SOA which runs on that infrastructure. In addition, it is the integration point for an underlying Infrastructure as a Service (IaaS) construct and the rest of the SOA in the wider context of cloud computing. Key requirements for this layer are outlined in the capability section describing the capabilities provided to fulfill those requirements.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;== Capabilities&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;There are multiple categories of capabilities that the Operational Systems Layer needs to support.">
  <properties
      key="drill down"
      value="id-8bf106e1-83e1-11e9-27b3-44850074a0ae"/>
  <properties
      key="difi:namespace"
      value="togsoara"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:type"
      value="archi:grouping"/>
  <properties
      key="label"
      value="${name}"/>
  <properties
      key="difi:language"
      value="en"/>
  <properties
      key="difi:name_no"/>
  <properties
      key="difi:name_en"
      value="Operational Systems Layer"/>
  <properties
      key="difi:description_no"/>
  <properties
      key="difi:description_en"
      value="== Overview&#xD;&#xA;All runtime elements of architecture reside in this layer. Effectively, this layer can conceptually be thought of as the runtime or deployment time of the solution. If we conduct a thought experiment and “freeze” the operations within this layer in a frame of time and expand it out, we will discover the separation of concerns that tend to cluster building blocks within the architecture: the aspects most closely connected with the consumption of the services, the processes that are choreographed into a flow, the services whose interfaces are exposed for consumption, the Service Components that will ultimately be used to realize the implementation of the services, along with the other four major cross-cutting and supporting concerns (integration, information, Quality of Service (QoS) factors, and governance).&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;== Context and Typical Flow&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;This layer describes the runtime and deployment infrastructure; the programs, platforms, application servers, containers, runtime environments, packaged applications, virtual machines, etc. that are on the hardware and are needed to support the SOA solution. These specifically include:&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;* All software and hardware infrastructure necessary to support the SOA and its components at runtime and design time (tools)&#xD;&#xA;* All operational and runtime hosting of underlying physical system components&#xD;&#xA;* All assets required to support the functionality of services in the SOA, including custom or packaged application assets, new services, services created through composition or orchestration, infrastructure services, etc. &#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;This layer represents a “snapshot” and logical categorization and generalization of the runtime environment. As such, this layer supports all the capabilities of the infrastructure that are needed for running/executing all software. Therefore, this layer supports the execution of the capabilities and responsibilities of the other layers of the SOA RA, including the components implementing the services; i.e., those components that a service relies on for providing it with its functional capabilities.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;For example, if we have a capability for an SOA that involves systems using mainframe and J2EE platforms, the Operational Systems Layer would instantiate the necessary Architecture Building Blocks (ABBs) in the Integration Layer and Service Component Layer and the underlying mainframe and J2EE components which provide the functional capability.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;We can express this as a formula such as:&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;Operational Systems Layer = [Infrastructural elements of all other layers] + [Underlying infrastructure to run the infrastructural elements (i.e., Operating Systems, etc.)] + [Elements that realize the Functional Components of services]&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;Thus this layer provides the building blocks supporting the operational systems which implement the functional capabilities of the other horizontal layers and the supporting/cross-cutting layers. In particular, the capabilities supported by this layer include providing operational and runtime hosting, infrastructure services and infrastructure virtualization, functional delivery support including support for service implementations, and realizations.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;== Connection Point with Other Initiatives or Standards&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;This layer represents the intersection point between the actual runtime infrastructure and the rest of the SOA which runs on that infrastructure. In addition, it is the integration point for an underlying Infrastructure as a Service (IaaS) construct and the rest of the SOA in the wider context of cloud computing. Key requirements for this layer are outlined in the capability section describing the capabilities provided to fulfill those requirements.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;== Capabilities&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;There are multiple categories of capabilities that the Operational Systems Layer needs to support."/>
</archimate:Grouping>
