<archimate:BusinessProcess
    xmlns:archimate="http://www.archimatetool.com/archimate"
    name="Define Architectural Approach"
    id="138e614b-9dc7-4190-861b-248fe6dec52f"
    documentation="The architectural approach to MDM depends on business strategy, the platforms of existing data sources, and the data itself, particularly its lineage and volatility, and the implications of high or low latency. Architecture must account for data consumption and sharing models. Tooling for maintenance depends on both business requirements and architecture options. Tooling helps define and is dependent on the approach to stewardship and maintenance.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;The number of source systems to be integrated into the Master Data solution and the platforms of those systems need to be accounted for when determining the approach to integration. The size and geographic spread of an organization will also influence the integration approach. Small organizations may effectively utilize a transaction hub whereas a global organization with multiple systems is more likely to utilize a registry. An organization with ‘siloed’ business units and various source systems may decide that a consolidated approach is the correct path to follow. Business domain experts, Data Architects, and Enterprise Architects should provide perspective on approach.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;The data sharing hub architecture is particularly useful when there is no clear system of record for Master Data. In this case, multiple systems supply data. New data or updates from one system can be reconciled with data already supplied by another system. The data-sharing hub becomes the source of Master Data content for data warehouses or marts, reducing the complexity of extracts and the processing time for data transformation, remediation, and reconciliation. Of course, data warehouses must reflect changes made to the data-sharing hub for historical purposes, while the data-sharing hub itself may need to reflect just the current state.">
  <properties
      key="difi:namespace"
      value="dmbok2"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:type"
      value="archi:business-process"/>
  <properties
      key="label"
      value="${name}"/>
  <properties
      key="difi:language"
      value="en"/>
  <properties
      key="difi:name_no"/>
  <properties
      key="difi:name_en"
      value="Define Architectural Approach"/>
  <properties
      key="difi:description_no"/>
  <properties
      key="difi:description_en"
      value="The architectural approach to MDM depends on business strategy, the platforms of existing data sources, and the data itself, particularly its lineage and volatility, and the implications of high or low latency. Architecture must account for data consumption and sharing models. Tooling for maintenance depends on both business requirements and architecture options. Tooling helps define and is dependent on the approach to stewardship and maintenance.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;The number of source systems to be integrated into the Master Data solution and the platforms of those systems need to be accounted for when determining the approach to integration. The size and geographic spread of an organization will also influence the integration approach. Small organizations may effectively utilize a transaction hub whereas a global organization with multiple systems is more likely to utilize a registry. An organization with ‘siloed’ business units and various source systems may decide that a consolidated approach is the correct path to follow. Business domain experts, Data Architects, and Enterprise Architects should provide perspective on approach.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;The data sharing hub architecture is particularly useful when there is no clear system of record for Master Data. In this case, multiple systems supply data. New data or updates from one system can be reconciled with data already supplied by another system. The data-sharing hub becomes the source of Master Data content for data warehouses or marts, reducing the complexity of extracts and the processing time for data transformation, remediation, and reconciliation. Of course, data warehouses must reflect changes made to the data-sharing hub for historical purposes, while the data-sharing hub itself may need to reflect just the current state."/>
</archimate:BusinessProcess>
