<archimate:BusinessProcess
    xmlns:archimate="http://www.archimatetool.com/archimate"
    name="Evaluate and Assess Data Sources"
    id="54724370-2b6b-43b3-b025-52479c29801c"
    documentation="Data in existing applications forms the basis of a Master Data Management effort. It is important to understand the structure and content of this data and the processes through which it is collected or created. One outcome from an MDM effort can be improvements in Metadata generated through the effort to assess the quality of existing data. One goal of assessment is to understand how complete data is with respect to the attributes that comprise Master Data. This process includes clarifying the definitions and granularity of those attributes. Semantic issues will arise at some point when defining and describing attributes. The Data Stewards will need to collaborate with the business areas on reconciliation and agreement on attribute naming and enterprise level definitions. (See Chapters 3 and 13.)&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;The other part of assessing sources is to understand the quality of the data. Data quality problems will complicate a Master Data project, so the assessment process should include addressing root causes of data issues. Never assume that data will be of high quality – it is safer to assume that is it not of high quality. Always assess its quality and suitability for a Master Data environment.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;The biggest challenge, as noted, will be disparity between sources. Data may be of high quality within any given source, but still not fit together with data from other sources, due to structural differences and differences in the values by which similar attributes are represented. Master Data initiatives provide the opportunity to define and implement standards in applications in which data is created or collected.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;For some Master Data entities, such as client, customer, or vendor, it is possible to purchase standardized data (such as Reference Directories) to enable the MDM effort. Several vendors have services that will supply cleansed data related to individual people or business entities or professions (e.g., health care professionals), that can be compared to an organization’s internal data to improve contact information, addresses, and names (see Chapter 10). In addition to assessing the quality of existing data, it also necessary to understand the technology that supports the collection of inputs to an MDM effort. Existing technology will influence the architectural approach to MDM.">
  <properties
      key="difi:namespace"
      value="dmbok2"/>
  <properties
      key="dct:type"
      value="archi:business-process"/>
  <properties
      key="label"
      value="${name}"/>
  <properties
      key="difi:language"
      value="en"/>
  <properties
      key="difi:name_no"/>
  <properties
      key="difi:name_en"
      value="Evaluate and Assess Data Sources"/>
  <properties
      key="difi:description_no"/>
  <properties
      key="difi:description_en"
      value="Data in existing applications forms the basis of a Master Data Management effort. It is important to understand the structure and content of this data and the processes through which it is collected or created. One outcome from an MDM effort can be improvements in Metadata generated through the effort to assess the quality of existing data. One goal of assessment is to understand how complete data is with respect to the attributes that comprise Master Data. This process includes clarifying the definitions and granularity of those attributes. Semantic issues will arise at some point when defining and describing attributes. The Data Stewards will need to collaborate with the business areas on reconciliation and agreement on attribute naming and enterprise level definitions. (See Chapters 3 and 13.)&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;The other part of assessing sources is to understand the quality of the data. Data quality problems will complicate a Master Data project, so the assessment process should include addressing root causes of data issues. Never assume that data will be of high quality – it is safer to assume that is it not of high quality. Always assess its quality and suitability for a Master Data environment.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;The biggest challenge, as noted, will be disparity between sources. Data may be of high quality within any given source, but still not fit together with data from other sources, due to structural differences and differences in the values by which similar attributes are represented. Master Data initiatives provide the opportunity to define and implement standards in applications in which data is created or collected.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;For some Master Data entities, such as client, customer, or vendor, it is possible to purchase standardized data (such as Reference Directories) to enable the MDM effort. Several vendors have services that will supply cleansed data related to individual people or business entities or professions (e.g., health care professionals), that can be compared to an organization’s internal data to improve contact information, addresses, and names (see Chapter 10). In addition to assessing the quality of existing data, it also necessary to understand the technology that supports the collection of inputs to an MDM effort. Existing technology will influence the architectural approach to MDM."/>
</archimate:BusinessProcess>
